{"tossups": [{"question": "The aftermath of this event led to the creation of the Quadruple Alliance and the formation of the 38 state German Confederation. It restored the Bourbon Dynasty in France with Louis XVIII. This meeting was interrupted by the Hundred Days and it was headed by Austrian minister Klemens von Metternich. For ten points, name this 1815 meeting that sought to organize post-Napoleonic Europe.", "answer": "<b> Congress of Vienna</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "This document calls one leader a \u201cdread sovereign\u201d and advocates to \u201ccombine ourselves together in a civil body politic.\u201d It was dated using the Julian Calendar instead of the Gregorian Calendar, and it was recorded in a journal by William Bradford. For ten points, name this 1620 agreement signed by the pilgrims who founded Plymouth Colony.", "answer": "<b> Mayflower Compact</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "In 2012, this man announced a \u201cReturn to Sovereignty\u201d day. This man, who accused the show Asa Zuba! of slander, leads a coalition between the NKP and his Liberal Democrats. He recently updated the\u201cthree-arrows\u201d of his namesake economics but has been criticized for numerous visits to the Yasukuni Shrine. For ten points, name this current Prime Minster of Japan.", "answer": "Shinzo<b> Abe</b>", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {}, {"question": "Marc Dubois suffered from this condition as the pilot of Air France Flight 447, which crashed in 2009. World records for this condition are no longer maintained due to fear of harm, but the last scientifically documented record for this condition is Randy Gardner\u2019s 264 hours. Tracy Morgan was injured in a bus accident caused by a Walmart truck driver suffering from this condition. For ten points, name this condition that causes irritability and yawning.", "answer": "<b> sleep deprivation</b> (accept<b> insomnia</b> and equivalents like<b> fatigue</b>,<b> exhaustion</b>,<b> tiredness</b>, or a general<b> lack of sleep</b>) Page 1", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "Theodore Parker and Gerrit Smith were part of the Secret Six that funded this man\u2019s actions. The Fugitive Slave Act prompted this man to create The League of the Gileadites. His son was killed by the forces of John Reid in Osawatomie. The Sack of Lawrence prompted this man to participate in the Pottawatomie Massacre. Robert E. Lee stopped this man from attempting to overtake a federal armory in West Virginia. For ten points, name this abolitionist who led an 1859 raid on Harper\u2019s Ferry.", "answer": "John<b> Brown</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {"question": "This man gave the Appeal of 18 June Speech during one war. This leader\u2019s opposition to the European Commission led to the Empty Chair Crisis. He was later criticized after Expo 67 for proclaiming \u201cLong live free Quebec!\u201d This man\u2019s government ended a conflict with the FLN by signing the Evian Accords. He was brought to power in the May Crisis, leading to the formation of the Fifth Republic. For ten points, name this French Prime Minister who led the Free French Forces during WWII.", "answer": "Charles de<b> Gaulle</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "erxes the Great built a throne hall with one hundred of these features in Persepolis. The term entasis refers to the gradual decrease in these objects\u2019 diameter as they rise, removing the optical illusion that these objects bend inward. One style of these objects uses a scroll for the capital; in addition to that Ionic type, these objects come in Doric and Corinthian orders. For ten points, name these architectural elements which usually bear the weight of a roof or ceiling.", "answer": "<b> column</b>s or<b> pillar</b>s <b>Second Quarter</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Other Fine Arts - Architecture"}, {"question": "During a drunken brawl, this man killed his officer Cleitus the Black, who had earlier saved this man\u2019s life during the Battle of the Granicus River. This man\u2019s successors were known as the Diadochi [dee-AH-doh-kee], and this rider of Bucephalus defeated Darius III at the Battle of Gaugamela. For ten points, name this son of Phillip II, a king of Macedon who conquered Persia.", "answer": "<b> Alexander the Great</b>", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "In 2008, FiveThirtyEight.com only failed to predict this state\u2019s Presidential result. Robert Kennedy\u2019s speech after the death of Martin Luther King was given in this state, shortly after speeches that day at Ball State and Notre Dame universities here. In 2015, the review website Angie\u2019s List cancelled a planned expansion of its headquarters in this state after the Religious Freedom Restoration Act was passed and signed by its governor, Mike Pence. For ten points, name this \u201cHoosier\u201d state.", "answer": "<b> Indiana</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "A \u201ctattered man\u201d in this novel bothers the protagonist, who is given a yellow envelope to deliver to Wilson\u2019s family upon his death, though Wilson asks for it back. In this novel, Henry Fleming is hit in the head with a rifle, leading his fellow soldiers to think he suffered the title wound. For ten points, name this Civil War novel written by Stephen Crane.", "answer": "The<b> Red Badge of Courage</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Short Fiction"}, {}, {"question": "One of these people is the title character of an opera which was revised to add a \u201cPolish act\u201d and ends with the Holy Fool lamenting his country\u2019s fate in Kromy Forest. In another opera, Ivan Susanin sacrifices himself for this title leader. The lead-up to the Time of Troubles was chronicled in Modest Mussorgsky\u2019s opera about one of these monarchs,<em> Boris Godunov</em>. For ten points, Mikhail Glinka wrote an opera about <em>A Life For</em> what leaders of the Russian Empire?", "answer": "<b> tsar</b>s", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {}, {"question": "The \u201cliquidators\u201d dealt with the aftermath of this event, which was detected after a day in Forsmark, Sweden. The Red Forest was created by this event, which led to a \u201czone of alienation\u201d being marked around the city of Pripyat. It was triggered by a poorly-safeguarded experiment in which control rods were manually removed, spreading radiation over much of Europe. For ten points, name this 1986 nuclear meltdown in modern Ukraine.", "answer": "<b> Chernobyl</b> nuclear disaster [or equivalent]", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This man described the arrival of the first African slaves into his home colony in a letter to Edwin Sandys. This man, who traveled with his family back to England on the</b> <b>ship (+)</b> <b>ship (+)</b> <em><b>Treasurer</b></em><b>, created the Varina Farms plantation and married a woman christened</b> <b>(*)</b> Rebecca after her conversion to Christianity. For ten points, name this early American settler who Rebecca after her conversion to Christianity. For ten points, name this early American settler who developed tobacco as a cash crop in Virginia and married Pocahontas.", "answer": "John<b> Rolfe</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Some of this company\u2019s Turbocharged Direct Injection, or TDI, engines controversially</b> <b>did not require the use of AdBlue urea solution to control the production of (+)</b> <b>nitrogen</b> <b>oxides. In September 2015, this company\u2019s use of \u201cdefeat device\u201d software was revealed when the EPA charged this company with (*) </b> cheating on emission testing with hundreds of thousands of its diesel-powered cars. For ten points, name this German automaker of the Golf, Jetta, and Beetle, whose name loosely translates to \u201cPeople\u2019s Car.\u201d", "answer": "<b> Volkswagen</b> Group", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {"question": "<b>In 1855, Napoleon III commissioned a classification system for this commodity, produced</b> <b>by Haut-Brion and Chateau Margaux. Prominent (+)</b> <b>growing regions for this product</b> <b>include France\u2019s \u201cgolden slope,\u201d though the 1976 Judgment of Paris proved the quality of (*) </b> California\u2019s production of varieties like Cabernet Sauvignon. For ten points, name this alcoholic beverage produced in Burgundy and Bordeaux from grapes.", "answer": "<b> wine</b>", "metadata": "Geography - Geography"}, {}, {"question": "<b>Mediation in this agreement was performed by Cyrus Vance. This agreement affirmed</b> <b>the importance of UN Security Council Resolution 242. (+)</b> <b>Tensions rose after its signing</b> <b>due to assumption of King Hussein\u2019s willingness to agree to its terms. It led to a framework for the eventual return of the Sinai Peninsula. (*)</b> Menachem Begin and Anwar Sadat shared the 1978 Nobel Peace Prize shortly after signing, for ten points, what agreement between Israel and Egypt guided by Jimmy Carter at a presidential retreat?", "answer": "<b> Camp David Accords</b> Page 8", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "<b>A parrot rests on a sign in one work by this artist, in which a cat, an ox, a rabbit, and an elk represent the Four Humors. A demon under a rainbow holds a sign bearing the title of this artist\u2019s (+)</b><em><b> Melencolia I</b></em><b>. This artist incorrectly added a horn to his depiction of an animal that had been given to Lisbon by Indian diplomats in 1515, and showed (*)</b> Famine, War, Plague, and Death trampling peasants in another work. For ten points, name this German creator of woodcuts like the<em> Four Horsemen of the Apocalypse</em> and<em> Rhinoceros</em>.", "answer": "Albrecht<b> D\u00a8urer</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Visual Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>This man threatened to kill Dennis Wilson, a Beach Boy, for changing the lyrics to his song \u201cCease to Exist.\u201d Vincent Bugliosi used circumstantial evidence to convict this man of conspiracy to (+) murder. He predicted a chaotic white vs. black war triggered by his music and that of the (*)</b> Beatles; this man called that conflict Helter Skelter. For ten points, name this man who, in 1969, ordered Sharon Tate and eight other people to be murdered by his so-called \u201cFamily.\u201d", "answer": "Charles<b> Manson</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Thomas Percy and Charles Neville attempted to overthrow this monarch in the Rising of the North. This monarch supported the Dutch in one conflict by signing the Treaty of Nonsuch, and Francis Walsingham uncovered a plot to assassinate this monarch by Anthony</b> <b>(+)</b> <b>Babington, which led to the execution of this monarch\u2019s cousin, Mary Stuart. This</b> <b>monarch spoke of having a \u201cheart and stomach of a (*)</b> king\u201d in a speech to troops at Tilbury. The Spanish Armada targeted, for ten points, what \u201cVirgin Queen\u201d of England?", "answer": "<b> Elizabeth I</b> of England  (1) <b>Artist George Catlin specialized in portraiture of these people. J.P. Morgan</b> <b>funded Edward Curtis\u2019 project to photographically document the lives of these</b> <b>people. Korczak Ziolkowski began sculpting a (+)</b> <b>monument to one of these people</b> <b>in 1948; that unfinished monument is less than twenty miles from Mount Rushmore</b> <b>on the (*) </b> sacred Thunderhead Mountain. For ten points, name these people, including Crazy Horse, a member of the Oglala Sioux. ANSWER:<b> Native American</b>s (accept American<b> Indian</b>s)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {}], "bonuses": []}